让我们来谈谈接口如何帮助实现一个新的想法
Let's talk about how interfaces help with a new idea
称为子类型。
called subtyping.
所以回想一下第一次阅读时，类型是一组值。
So recall from the first reading that type is a set of values.
现在，在Java中，列表类型是由接口定义的。
Now, in Java, the list type is defined by an interface.
所以如果我们考虑所有可能的列表值，
So if we think about all possible list values,
它们实际上都不是列表对象。
none of them are actually list objects.
我们无法创建接口的实例。
We can't create instances of an interface.
相反，这些值都是数组列表对象，链接列表
Instead, those values are all array list objects, linked list
对象，或其他类的对象
objects, or objects of some other class
实现列表的。
that implements list.
所以子类型只是父类型的一个子集。
So a subtype is simply a subset of the supertype.
数组列表和链接列表是列表的子类型。
Array list and linked list are subtypes of list.
而短语b是一种手段的亚型，
And the phrase b is a subtype of a means,
一般来说，每个b值都是a值。
in general, every b value is an a value.
或者就规格而言，这意味着
Or in terms of specifications, what this means is
每一个值，每一个b的实例，每一个b的类型，
that every value, every instance of b, of the type b,
符合a型规范。
satisfies the spec for type a.
所以这意味着b只是a的一个子类型
So that means that b is only a subtype of a
如果b的规格至少和a的规格一样强
if b's specification is at least as strong as a's specification
因此每个b值也将满足
so that every b value will also satisfy
所有的要求都加上了a值。
all of the requirements put on an a value.
现在，让我们回到Java，当
Now, bringing us back to Java, when
我们声明他们的类--
we declare their class that implement--
当我们声明一个类
that a class implements-- when we declare a class that
实现一个接口，Java编译器
implements an interface, the Java compiler
自动执行此要求的一部分。
enforces part of this requirement automatically.
例如，它确保
For example, it ensures that every method in a appears
在具有兼容类型签名的b中
in b with a compatible type signature
因此，对于
so that a b value could be used in place of-- for a client that
期望a值能够调用所有方法
is expecting an a value would be able to call all the methods
它需要召唤。
that it needs to call.
所以b类不能实现接口a
So class b can't implement interface a
除非它实现了a中声明的所有方法。
unless it implements all of the methods declared in a.
不幸的是，编译器不能
Unfortunately, the compiler can't
检查我们没有在其他方面削弱这个规格
check that we haven't weakened the spec in other ways
当我们申报b。
when we declare b.
不能确定我们是否
It can't check that we-- whether we've
加强了对一种方法的某些投入的先决条件，
strengthened the precondition on some inputs to a method,
我们是否削弱了一些
whether we've weakened a postcondition on some
我们能否保证
of the outputs, whether we can guarantee
接口抽象类型向其客户播发的。
that the interface abstract type advertises to its clients.
所以，如果您在Java中声明一个子类型——换句话说，
So if you declare a subtype in Java-- in other words,
如果你宣布你正在实施
if you declare that you're implementing
一个接口——那么您必须确保
an interface-- then you must ensure
子类型规范至少是
that that subtype spec is at least as
强如超模规格，不仅仅是
strong as the supertype spec, not just
在它的方法类型声明中，也在实际的规范中。
in its method type declarations, but also in the actual specs.